Finding Aid for Chris Kolb papers, 1997-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Chris Kolb papers 1997-2006
Kolb, Chris.
1 linear foot
0733 Aa 2
Chris Kolb was a Democratic State Representative for the Michigan House of Representatives representing the 53rd district (Ann Arbor and Pittsfield Township) from January 2001 to January 2007. Kolb's papers include legislative files mainly relating to gay issues, including gay marriage and hate crime legislation.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were donated by Chris Kolb (donor no. 9839 ) in January 2007.
The collection is open to research.
Chris Kolb was a Democratic State Representative for the 53rd district (Ann Arbor and Pittsfield Township) from January 2001 to January 2007. He was especially involved in legislative issues relating to gay rights, land use and the environment, and health insurance.
Kolb's papers include legislative files mainly relating to gay issues, including gay marriage and hate crime legislation. The Kolb papers have been divided into two series: Career Files and Legislative Files.
Subjects:
Kolb, Chris.; Legislators--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Gay rights--Michigan.; Same-sex marriage--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Hate crimes--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--2001-2010.
- Career Files, 2002-2006
  Kolb's Career Files (0.1 linear feet, 2002-2006) includes files on Kolb's political career including his political campaign advertisements. Also found in this series are files on Kolb's participation in the Henry Toll Fellowship program which includes some background information on Kolb's career.
  - Ann Arbor advertisements (political campaign), 2002-2006 (Box 1)
  - Henry Toll Fellowship, 2002 (Box 1)
  - St. Mary's Christian Fellowship Image Award, 2003 (Box 1)
- Legislative Files, 1997-2006
  Kolb's Legislative Files (0.9 linear feet, 1997-2006) make up the bulk of the material in his papers. The files are mainly topical research files relating to different issues that Kolb was involved in while a member of the Michigan House of Representatives.
  - Articles (Michigan related), 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Attorney General/Proposal 2, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Call to order speeches, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Conscientious Objection Package (House Bill 5006), 2004 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2006 (Box 1)
  - Co-sponsorship-same season sports, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Domestic partnership benefits, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Domestic violence legislation-unemployment insurance (House Bill 5508) (Box 1)
  - Environmental issues, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
  - Gay marriage, 2003-2004, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Hate crimes
    - General, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - House bills (includes old Lynne Martinez files, HB 4674, 1997/1998) (Box 1)
    - Pride rally, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Health insurance, 2001, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender issues (LGBT)
    - Kwame Kilpatrick, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Non-discrimination, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Second parent adoptions, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Ten Commandments (HB 4433), 2005 (Box 1)